eligreg@gmail.com 301.602.0853

Well over a decade of iOS development, I've built a wide variety of tasteful apps for companies at all sizes, with a keen product sense, natural design instincts, and deep engineering curiosity. I'm comfortable making sustainable, best-practice decisions, iterating quickly and prioritizing the needs of the business. I obsess on the details and won't ship unless I'm confident in the product. My sweet spot is building apps from 0 to 1.

IOS

- Modern Stack: Swift, SwiftUI, Swift Concurrency, Swift Packages (modular feature development), Swift Data (local storage), TCA (3rd party architecture: composable & testable), REST & GraphQL (Networking), Xcode Cloud (CI/CD), Swift Testing (unit testing), ViewInspector (3rd party SwiftUI view unit testing), TestFlight (beta distribution), Instruments (app profiling), Xcode & ChatGPT Plus & Cursor (accelerated development, testing & documentation writing)
- Legacy: Objective-C, UIKit, MVC, Core Data, Grand Central Dispatch (GCD), Combine, Storyboards, XIBs, CocoaPods, Carthage

EXPERIENCE

• Freemodel Remote

Senior Software Engineer, iOS Client Apps

July 2022 - December 2024

- Early hire to venture backed Silicon Valley startup, the "Uber for home remodeling" built, tested, shipped and iterated client app from 0 to 1 (feature complete).
- Developed a digital platform that automated 95% of previously manual business operations. Digital
 platform allows the company to expand from California to US nationwide with little need for additional
 human capital.
- Contributed 44.3% of surviving lines of code for codebase with 5 contributors, over 2.5 years.
- Led tech eval of Skip.tools, a Swift & SwiftUI to Kotlin & Jetpack Compose transpiler for cross platform app development. Submit report largely focused on cost to business and projected product outcome.
- Tactfully built foundational infrastructure and established early architectural patterns, balancing velocity with longer term sustainable code.

[crunchbase]

• Esri Portland, Oregon

 $Product\ Owner,\ ArcGIS\ Open\ Source\ Apps$

June 2019 - June 2021

November 2017 - June 2019

- Led a multi-disciplinary team building a portfolio of 14 location based apps across 7 platforms, published in open source. Github community insights reported 100+ daily unique clones, collectively.
- Smaller team size required me to adopt multiple roles (Product, Developer, Designer, Documentation Writer, GIS Analyst.)
- Fostered community as an ArcGIS developer advocate on the ArcGIS for developers website, at Esri flagship events (Developer Summit, User Conference), and at quarterly Meetups in the Portland R&D center.

developers.arcgis.com

• Esri Portland, Oregon

iOS Software Engineer, ArcGIS Open Source Apps

• Primary iOS developer of 3 location based apps, published in open source. Engaged with open source community through documentation and Github. Published UIs in open source toolkit.

- Authored 14+ tutorials teaching how to develop apps using the ArcGIS Runtime API for iOS.
- Featured speaker of open source technology products to a crowd of 3K at the 2019 Esri Developer Summit Plenary in Palm Springs, CA.

• Moishe House Foundation

Remote

iOS Software Engineer & Technical Team Lead

July 2015 - July 2017

- Technical lead for org's internal operations software reaching thousands of users annually.
- Developed iOS app assisting org with accounting millions (\$) in annual spending on community programming.
- Architected mobile API for Ruby on Rails back end.

[moishehouse.org]

• Dot Dot Dash Inc. iOS Software Engineer Portland, Oregon

June 2014 - July 2015

- Built iOS app controlling LED holiday lights using BLE; lights sold in Apple stores winter 2014 holiday season.
- Built iOS camera app to accompany lenses affixable to mobile devices.
- Assisted in development and installation of generative, experiential art installations.

[dotdotdash.io]

• The John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts

Washington, D.C.

September 2010 - 2014

- iOS Software Engineer & Software QA Engineer

• QA for digital platform of online arts integrated educational content.

- Developed Arts Days Twitter Bot posting engaging tweets daily.
- Developed Arts Days iOS App shown in Apple's 2013 WWDC Keynote.

[kennedy-center.org]

• Kibbutz Lotan Center for Creative Ecology

Hevel Eilot, Israel

 $Ecological\ Volunteer$

July 2011 - November 2011

- Assisted research project analyzing the energy efficiency of structures built using earthen materials vs traditional cinderblock; Ben Gurion University.
- Learned permaculture and sustainability.

[kibbutzlotan.com]

Additional Platforms

- GIS & Mapping: ArcGIS Maps SDK (Native platforms), ArcGIS Online, ArcGIS API for Python, ArcGIS Pro, Apple MapKit
- Web Apps: Node & Express JS, Gatsby JS, Ruby on Rails, Python Flask, Python Django
- Embedded Systems: Arduino, Pixel Pusher, Raspberry Pi

EDUCATION

• Indiana University

Bloomington, Indiana

B.S. Informatics @ School of Informatics, Computing and Engineering

2010

o Double Minor: Fine Arts (Graphic Design), Telecommunications

LIFESTYLE & INTERESTS

• Scuba Certified, Wilderness Backpacker, Community Leader, Code Mentor, WIT Advocate, Travel Enthusiast.